## Abhisek Kundu

CONTACT Information Lally 02, Computer Science, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 110 8th Street, Troy, NY 12180, USA

E-mail: abhisekkundu@gmail.com Web: www.cs.rpi.edu/~kundua2

OBJECTIVE

Obtaining full-time position in Machine Learning/Data Mining/Algorithms.

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research spans machine learning, compressive sensing, and randomized algorithms in numerical linear algebra. Specifically, I am working on various probabilistic techniques to sample a small number of elements from a matrix to perform tasks such as sparsification (producing a sparse matrix from fully observed data) and reconstruction (recovering the original matrix from partially-observed data). These methods are useful in efficient large-scale data analysis (e.g. social networks analysis, bioinformatics, image processing, text/web mining) and matrix completion (e.g. recommendation systems).

**EDUCATION** 

# Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, New York, USA

Ph.D., Computer Science, August 2015

• Dissertation Topic: "Element-wise Matrix Sparsifiaction and Reconstruction"

• Advisor: Petros Drineas

# The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA

M.S., Computer Science and Engineering, 2012

• Advisor: Luis Rademacher

### Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India

B.E., Computer Science and Engineering, 2006

• Advisor: Atal Chaudhuri

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

### Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, New York USA

Graduate Research Assistant, Computer Science Department January 2013 - present Working on various projects on randomized algorithms in numerical linear algebra, optimization, and machine learning.

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Computer Science Department

August - December, 2012

Grading Machine Learning course.

## The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio USA

Graduate Research Assistant

January - March, 2012

Worked on randomized algorithms for column subset selection problem.

Instructor/Graduate Teaching Assistant March - May, September - December, 2011 Taught undergraduate course on Programming and Algorithms in Computer Science and Engineering Department. Responsibilities included lectures, preparing homework, lab assignments, and examination questions, grading, and proctoring.

• CSE202 Introduction to Programming and Algorithms for Engineers and Scientists, Spring and Autumn 2011.

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2009 - March, 2011

Worked on various projects on gene expression data analysis and genetic network analysis.

Publications and • A. Kundu Relaxed Leverage Sampling for Low-rank Matrix Completion.

Working Papers http://arxiv.org/pdf/1503.06379.pdf, 2015.

- A. Kundu, P. Drineas, M. Magdon-Ismail. Approximating Sparse PCA from Incomplete Data. http://arxiv.org/pdf/1503.03903.pdf, 2015.
- A. Kundu, P. Drineas, M. Magdon-Ismail. Recovering PCA from Hybrid- $(\ell_1, \ell_2)$  Sparse Sampling of Data Elements.

http://arxiv.org/pdf/1503.00547.pdf, 2015.

- A. Kundu, P. Drineas. *Identifying Influential Entries in a Matrix*. 2015 (working).
- A. Kundu, P. Drineas, M. Magdon-Ismail. CUR-based Element-wise Matrix Reconstruction. 2015 (working).
- A. Kundu, P. Drineas. A Note on Randomized Element-wise Matrix Sparsification. http://arxiv.org/pdf/1404.0320v1.pdf, 2014.
- P. Payne, K. Huang, K. Keen-Circle, A. Kundu, J. Zhang, T. Borlawsky. Multi-dimensional Discovery of Biomarker and Phenotype Complexes. BMC Bioinformatics 2010, 11(Suppl 9):S3
- A. Kundu, H.G. Ozer, T. Borlawsky, K. Keen-Circle, K. Huang, P. Payne. Clinical Attribute Network for Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia. IEEE BIBM 2009, (279 - 282).
- B. B. Chaudhuri, A. Kundu. Synthesis of Individual Handwriting in Bangla Script. International Conference on Frontiers in Handwriting Recognition, 2008.
- A. Kundu, A. Chaudhuri, D. Ghosh, S. Bhattacharyya, A. Chaudhuri. Watermarking in JPEG2000 Coding Pipeline Using Quantization Index Modulation. International Conference on Information Technology, Vol-I, 144-150, ISSN 0973-6824, 2007.

### Professional EXPERIENCE

### George Edcare, Kolkata, India

Part-time Faculty

January - July, 2008

Worked as faculty in Mathematics at George Edcare in Kolkata, India. Duties included teaching, grading, and designing course materials for GRE and GMAT aspirants.

### Amdocs Product and Development Organization, Pune, India

Subject Matter Expert

July 2006 - June 2007

Worked as an expert in Software Development at Amdocs Product and Development Organization in India. Duties focused on incorporating customization on existing softwares, and developing new software products.

• Member of a team receiving special recognition from the CEO for the release of a new product, 2007.

### Computer Skills

- Coding: Matlab, Java, C, C++, Unix shell scripts, HTML, JavaScript, CSS.
- Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, Windows.
- Typography: Latex.